We were in a store
and a guy in that store
told us to put our uniforms on.
"what the hell are
you talking about?"
He says...
The USA is in
a war with Japan.
We couldn't believe it.
Well. our country
was attacked.
It's different.
It wasn't Iike
Korea or Vietnam.
We was attacked.
And. you know.
it was a feeling that...
maybe. we're just
dumb country people but.
where I come from.
but. a lot of us volunteered.
Who would like to
volunteer for the tank corps?
volunteer for the air force?
Who would like to
volunteer for the navy or whatever?
And then. they said.
"who would like to
volunteer for the airborne?"
Somebody says.
"what the hell's the airborne?"
Nobody ever heard of it.
We came from a
small. small town
and three fellas in that
town were. that were "4f".
committed suicide
because they couldn't go.
a different time.
I did things.
I didn't do 'em for medals.
I didn't do 'em for accolades.
I did 'em because
it's what had to be done.
The guy says.
"would you jump out of airplanes?
"You know.
you got all your army equipment
and you jump out of airplanes.
to fight the enemy."
These guys.
they said. "go to hell".
Nobody put up their hands.
And then. I don't know
what it was brought it up.
but the guy giving
the speech was saying.
"but you get paid
$50 a month more."
So. that made it
a hundred bucks.
Support us and become VIP member
to remove all ads from www.OpenSubtitles.org
I want a whiff of chicken pie.
Okay. boys.
let's get this gear stowed.
Fox company.
we go in five.
In the name of the father
and the son and of the holy...
1st platoon draw small arms.
Do you need a hand. lieutenant?
Easy company!
Listen up!
Gather up around me.
Just move it up.
c'mon. gentlemen.
Let's go!
Now. the channel coast
is socked in with rain and fog.
High winds on the drop zone.
No jump tonight.
The invasion has
been postponed.
We're on a 24 hour stand-down.
sonofabitch.
Drill sergeants. take charge.
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens
I rather expected it
Well. I can't see how you
people can pass up $80.000
for the cause.
For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause.
why don't you join the army?
Oh...
I think it's clearing up.
You think it's clearing up?
No.
I think it's clearing up.
How are your men?
They'll be fine.
Five o'clock in New York.
Four o'clock in Chicago.
Happy hour. huh?
Yeah.
Happy hour.
A couple of drinks.
maybe an early
dinner before the theater.
A civilized place
for civilized men.
Should've been
born earlier. Nix.
What. and give up all this?
We'll go to Chicago.
I'll take you there.
Yeah.
We'll see.
Actually. you know
who's from there?
Who?
Oh. him.
712 days of that
sonofabitch and here we are.
You people are at
the position of attention.
Private Perconte. have you
been blousing your trousers
over your boots
like a paratrooper?
No. sir.
Then explain the
creases at the bottom.
No excuse. sir.
Volunteering for the parachute
infantry is one thing. Perconte.
but you've got a long way
to prove that you belong here.
Your weekend pass is revoked.
Name?
Luz. George.
Dirt in the rear side aperture.
Pass revoked.
When did you sew on
these chevrons. sergeant Lipton?
Yesterday. sir.
Long enough to notice this.
Revoked.
Sir.
Name?
Malarkey. Donald G.
Malarkey?
Malarkey's slang
for bullshit. isn't it?
Yes. sir.
Rust on the butt plate
hinge spring. private bullshit.
Revoked.
Name?
Liebgott. Joseph D. sir.
Rusty bayonet. Liebgott.
You wanna kill Germans?
Yes. sir.
Not with this.
I wouldn't take this
rusty piece of shit to war.
and I will not take you
to war in your condition.
Now. thanks to these
men and their infractions.
every man in the company
who had a weekend pass.
has lost it.
Change into your pt gear.
we're running currahee.
2nd platoon fall out.
We have two minutes.
Fall out!
I ain't going up that hill.
Hey. Perconte.
what are you thinking of.
blousin' your pants?
Shut up. Martin. alright?
He gigged everybody.
Yeah. well.
you should know better.
Don't give him no excuses.
Excuses?
Why don't you come here.
look at these trousers.
get down and you tell me
if there's a crease on 'em?
Alright. let's go.
on the road in pt formation.
Let's move. move. move!
Perconte. let's go. Perconte.
Private white.
why are you not in your pt gear?
I asked you a question. private.
Oh. Easy company.
and while you're running.
don't worry.
we'll take your dames
to the movies for you.
Yeah. good. they need
some female company.
Where do we run?
Currahee.
And what does
"Currahee" mean?
We stand alone.
How far up.
how far down?
Three miles up.
three miles down.
And what company is this?
Easy company.
And what do we do?
Stand alone.
Do not help that man!
Do not help that man.
We do not stop.
You've got 30 minutes to
get to the top of this mountain
If you wanna serve
in the paratroopers.
Hi-ho. Silver!
C'mon. you can make it up there.
C'mon.
C'mon now. c'mon.
Alley. let's go.
C'mon. Guarnere.
Christenson. c'mon.
I never thought I'd see
the day. private Wynn.
We are coming on 23 minutes.
That may be good enough
for the rest of the 506.
but that is not good
enough for Easy company.
We can make it.
we can do this. c'mon.
I'm gonna say something.
To who?
Lieutenant Winters.
What is it?
Permission to speak. sir?
Permission granted.
Sir. we got nine companies. sir.
That we do.
Well. how come
we're the only company
marching every friday night.
12 miles. full pack.
in the pitch dark?
Why do you think.
private Randleman?
Lieutenant Sobel hates us. sir.
Lieutenant Sobel does
not hate Easy company.
private Randleman.
He just hates you.
Thank you. sir.
He hates him back.
He hates you too. Muck.
Lieutenant Winters.
I want canteens out of belts
With the caps unscrewed.
Easy company.
canteens out and open.
On my command. they will
pour the contents onto the ground.
On the co's order.
you will upend your canteen.
Now. lieutenant.
Pour 'em.
Who is this?
Christenson.
Why is there no
water in your canteen?
You drank from your
canteen. didn't you?
Sir. I...
Lieutenant Winters.
Yes. sir.
Was this man ordered
to not drink from his canteen
during the friday night march?
He was. sir.
Private Christenson.
you have disobeyed a direct order.
You will fill your canteen
and repeat all 12 miles
of the march immediately.
Yes. sir.
Fall out!
What in the name of god
are you doing with my company?
You're late and you allow troopers
to disobey direct orders?
No excuse. sir.
You're making me
look bad. lieutenant.
This is not Dog company.
This is not Fox company.
This. this is Easy company.
And under my command.
this will be the first
and finest company
in this regiment.
I want the names of six men.
their infractions
and your disciplinary
recommendations
on my desk by 0130.
Is that clear?
What infractions. sir?
Find some.
So. what'd you do?
Picked six men and
gave 'em latrine duty.
The lucky six?
McDonald. Toye. Perconte.
Lipton.
Muck and Guarnere.
Why them?
It was their turn.
Sobel's a genius.
I had a headmaster just
like him in prep school.
I know the type.
Lewis.
Michelangelo's a genius.
Beethoven's a genius.
You know a man
in this company
who wouldn't double-time
Currahee with a full pack
just to piss in that
guy's morning coffee?
Let's go. let's go.
Stand in the door.
Go.
One thousand.
two thousand.
You just broke both
your legs. private Gordon.
Are you trying to
get yourself killed?
No. sir.
Stand in the door.
Shit.
To the wall.
to the wall.
Over as a team.
Go on.
against the wall.
Jesus. what the hell is this?
That's pig guts. boy.
Goddammit!
Why are you here.
private Gordon?
I wanna be in
the airborne. sir.
I don't believe you.
Why are you here.
private Gordon?
I wanna be in
the airborne. sir.
You have 50 minutes
to the top and back.
and I will be watching you.
What are you waiting for?
Easy company has the
finest performance record
in the entire 2nd battalion.
I believe every bit of
that is thanks to you.
Congratulations.
captain Sobel.
Thank you. sir.
Isn't that lieutenant Winters
leading Easy company in pt?
Yes. sir.
He's a damned good man.
I was planning on giving
him a set of these today.
Why don't you do it?
He'd be proud to
get 'em from you.
Pornography.
contraband.
Non-regulation clothing.
This man had 200 prophylactic
kits in his footlocker.
How in the name of god was
he gonna have the strength
to fight the war?
How is it private.
private Tipper
Has spare time for so
much correspondence?
Captain. are personal letters
to be considered contraband?
These men aren't
paratroopers yet. lieutenant.
They have no personal property.
What is this?
Anybody?
Er. it's a can of peaches. sir.
Lieutenant Nixon thinks
this is a can of peaches.
That is incorrect. lieutenant.
Your weekend pass
is cancelled.
This is United States
Army property
Which was taken.
without authorization.
from my mess facility.
and I will not tolerate
thievery in my unit.
Whose footlocker is this?
Private Parkes. sir.
Get rid of him.
All weekend passes
are cancelled.
Officers included.
Carry on.
Lieutenant Winters.
Colonel sink has
seen fit to promote you.
As 1st lieutenant.
you'll serve as my executive officer.
Congratulations.
Thank you. sir.
And. as a test of your
organizational skills
and command potential.
I am designating you...
mess officer for 14 days.
Report to the mess
kitchen at 0515 hours.
Company breakfast
to be served at 0600.
Yes. sir.
Oh. and. Dick...
There's rain forecast tomorrow.
So the company will
have a light afternoon
of lecture and
classroom instruction.
I think a special meal
before their afternoon off
would be a welcome
change of pace.
Would you agree?
Yes. sir.
I like spaghetti.
Hold on.
more coming.
These guys are packing it away.
This stuff is orange.
Spaghetti ain't
supposed to be orange.
This ain't spaghetti.
This is army noodles
with ketchup.
You ain't gotta eat it.
Oh. c'mon. Gonorrhea.
as a fellow Italian.
you should know that
calling this crap spaghetti
is a mortal sin.
You don't want it.
I'll have it.
No. no. no.
I'm eating here.
Hey. get outta here.
Orders changed. get up!
Lectures are cancelled.
Easy company is
running up Currahee.
Move. move!
Three miles up.
three miles down.
Hi-ho. Silver!
Let's go.
let's go.
You're a washout.
private Hoobler!
You should pack up both
your ears and go home.
Looks like Gordon's done.
Aren't you. Gordon.
you finished?
You do not deserve
to get your wings.
Private Randleman.
you look tired.
There's an ambulance waiting
for you at the bottom of the hill.
It can all be over right now.
No more pain.
no more Currahee.
No more captain Sobel.
We pull upon the risers.
we fall upon the grass.
we never land upon our feet.
we always hit our ass.
Aye. aye. Christ almighty.
who the hell are we.
zim-zam. goddamn.
we're airborne infantry.
We pull upon the risers.
we fall upon the grass.
we never land upon our feet.
we always hit our ass.
Aye. aye. Christ almighty.
who the hell are we.
zim-zam. goddamn.
we're airborne infantry.
So. do we feel like we're
ready to be army paratroopers?
Yes. sergeant.
I hope so.
This'll be the first of five
exits from a c47 aircraft
scheduled for today.
Get ready.
Stand up.
Hook up.
Upon successful completion
of your fifth and final jump.
you'll be certified
army paratroopers.
Check equipment!
Sound-off for
equipment check!
Nine okay.
Eight okay.
Seven okay.
Six okay.
Five okay.
Four okay.
Three okay.
Two okay.
One okay.
There'll be a lot of men
dropping from the sky today.
Hopefully. under
deployed canopies.
Stand in the door!
I guarantee you're
gonna love it. lieutenant.
Go. go!
Jumping from 1000 feet
in sticks of 12
jumpers per aircraft.
All you have to do is
remember what you were taught.
and I guarantee you gravity
will take care of the rest.
Go. go. go. go!
Go. go. go!
Damnit.
And. gentlemen.
rest assured.
any refusals in the
aircraft or at the door...
and I guarantee you.
you will...
be out of the airborne.
Four okay.
Three okay.
Two okay.
One okay.
Stand in the door.
Go!
1000. 2000. 3000.
4000. 5000. 6000.
7000. 8000. 9000!
Hi-ho. Silver.
Now just think. if you had
any class or style like me.
Somebody might
mistake you for somebody.
You mean like
your fucking sergeant?
I'm just kidding.
Congratulations. Martin.
Corporal Toye. there will be
no leaning in my company.
Are those dusty
jump wings?
How do you expect
to slay the huns
with dust on
your jump wings?
Luz. just give me a drink.
Hell of an idea. Joe.
There you go.
Three miles up.
three miles down.
Ten-hut!
Well. at ease.
paratroopers.
Good evening.
Easy company.
Evening. sir.
Now. parachute infantry
is a brand new concept
in American military history.
But by God. the 506 is gonna
forge that brand new concept
into victory.
Yes. sir.
I want you to know
that I'm damned proud
of each and every one of you.
Now. you deserve this party.
Thank you.
sergeant Grant.
sir.
So. I want you to have fun...
and remember our motto...
Currahee!
Petty.
Map.
C'mon.
Ah. Christ.
We're in the wrong position.
We're textbook
position for ambush. sir.
We should sit tight.
let the enemy team
come into our killing zone.
They're right out
there somewhere.
Let's just get 'em.
Sir. we have
perfect cover here.
Lieutenant.
deploy your troops.
2nd platoon.
move out.
What?
Tactical column.
Captain.
you've just been killed.
along with 95%
of your company.
Your outfit?
Easy company.
2nd battalion 506th.
Leave three wounded
men on the ground
and report back to
the assembly area.
Goddammit.
You. you. you.
Well. what are you gonna do?
Nothing. just keep
training the men.
Am I interrupting?
No. no.
Lieutenant Lewis Nixon.
Lieutenant Harry Welsh.
just in from the 82nd.
Congratulations on the promotion.
Ah. thanks.
if you wanna call it that.
You'll learn him pretty quickly.
No flaws. no vices.
no sense of humor.
Just like your chums
up at battalion staff.
What's up?
I'm hearing a lot of rumblings.
Sobel?
Just talking about that.
So. he gets a little
jumpy in the field?
hmm-mmm.
He gets jumpy and
then you get killed.
That's nice.
Yeah. listen.
if we discuss it.
I think it should just
be amongst ourselves.
Oh. absolutely.
2nd platoon ready?
Ready. sir.
Then get them in formation.
We're moving out.
Yes. sir.
Shut up. Cobb.
Eh. you gotta admit it.
He's got no chance.
Either the krauts will get him.
or one of us.
Who. Sobel?
He screwed up one maneuver.
Well. you know.
I'm always fumbling with grenades.
It would be easy if one
went off by accident. you know?
Well. now they must have
put him in charge for a reason.
Yeah. 'cause the army wouldn't
make a mistake. right. Shift?
Going my way?
Wherever the train takes me.
Where do you
suppose that might be?
I haven't got a clue.
Yeah. c'mon.
take a guess.
Atlantic. Pacific.
Atlantic?
I'm not the intelligence officer.
mmm.
Well. as such. I of course know.
but if I told you.
I'd have to kill you.
So. don't tell me.
New York city.
Troop ship.
England.
We're invading Europe.
my friend.
Fortress Europa.
Since when do I drink?
If I thought you'd drink it.
I wouldn't offer it to you.
Nix?
What are you gonna do
when you get into combat?
Oh. I have every confidence
in my scrounging abilities.
And I have a case of vat 69
hidden in your footlocker.
Really?
Oh. yeah.
Morning.
mmm.
This could turn into
a real nice trip.
"Dear sir or madam.
soon your son will
drop from the sky
to engage and
defeat the enemy.
Your frequent letters of
love and encouragement
will arm him with
a fighting heart.
With that he cannot fail.
but will win glory for himself.
make you proud of him
and his country ever grateful
for his service in
its hour of need.
Signed Herbert M. Sobel.
captain commanding."
Right now. some lucky
bastard's headed for the south pacific.
Oh. what I'd give.
He's gonna get billeted
on some tropical island...
Keep talking.
Sitting under a palm tree
with six naked native girls.
helping him cut up coconuts
so he can hand-feed
'em to the flamingos.
Flamingos are mean.
They bite.
So do the naked native girls.
With any luck.
Hey. guys.
I'm glad I'm going to Europe.
Hitler gets one of these
right across the windpipe.
Roosevelt changes
thanksgiving to Joe Toye day.
and pays me 10 grand a year
for the rest of my fucking life.
What if we don't get to Europe?
What if they send
us to north Africa?
My brother's in north Africa.
He says it's hot.
Really. it's hot in Africa?
Shut up.
The point is.
it don't matter where we go.
Once we get into combat.
the only person you can trust
is yourself and
the fella next to you.
Hey. as long as
he's a paratrooper.
Oh. yeah?
And what if that paratrooper
turns out to be Sobel?
If I'm next to Sobel in combat.
I'm moving on down the line.
Hook up with
some other officer.
like Heyliger or Winters.
I like winters.
he's a good man.
But when the
bullets start flying.
I don't know if I want a
quaker doing my fighting for me.
How do you
know he's a quaker?
He ain't catholic.
Neither's Sobel.
That prick's the
son of Abraham.
He's what?
He's a Jew.
I'm a Jew.
Congratulations.
Get your nose
out of my face.
What's all that about?
Gonorrhea called
Sobel a Jew.
Liebgott took offense
'cause he's a Jew too.
Fighting over Sobel.
that's smart.
Attack!
No. you wanna kill him!
Parry right. parry left.
Thrust!
Take cover.
Okay.
Yesterday. we talked
about magnetic declination
and the left add.
right subtract rule.
Today we're gonna
put it into practice.
There are two basic
types of fighting positions.
The first is the
prepared position.
The advantages of
a prepared position
are that it gives you
cover and concealment.
Commence fire!
We'll then maneuver.
right in through these trees.
At the same time.
our 2nd platoon.
in this particular case.
moves over here.
He's then gonna close with
and kill or capture that German.
Sobel's late.
Why is there a fence here?
There should be no fence here.
Tipper!
Yes. sir.
Give me the map.
Perconte. Luz.
Get the men. get 'em b--
Take cover behind those trees.
Alright. you heard the word.
There should be no.
there should be no fence here.
Um...
We could go over it. sir.
Really?
That's not the point.
where are the goddamn--
Where the goddamn hell are we?
Perconte?
Yeah.
Sobel's lost again. right?
Yeah. he's lost.
Fucking Christ.
Can you do major Horton?
Does a wild bear
crap in the woods. son?
Shh. shh. shh.
Maybe the good major
can goose this schmuck.
Get us moving?
No way...
Oh yeah. yes.
You gotta. you gotta.
Alright. just this once.
Shh. shh.
Three five. six.
eight. three. three.
Isn't that the intersection?
No. sir. it's here.
You're a full grid off.
Goddammit.
Is there a problem.
captain Sobel?
Who said that?
Who broke silence?
I think it's major Horton. sir.
Major Horton?
What is he. did he join us?
I think maybe he's moving
between the platoons. sir.
What is the goddamn
holdup. Mr. Sobel?
A fence. sir.
Um. god...
A barbed wire fence.
Oh. that dog just
ain't gonna hunt.
Now. you cut that fence
and get this goddamn platoon
on the move!
Yes. sir!
Where are my
goddamn wire cutters?
We have to move.
Sir. without captain
Sobel and 1st platoon?
It's a T intersection.
We improvise.
Double envelopment
laid on a base of fire
to cut the road in all directions.
Hook right with 1st squad.
Tell Guarnere to
move left with 2nd.
I'll be right up the
middle with 3rd. go.
Yes. sir.
Deary me.
Bloody hell.
You've done it now. yanks.
You've captured me.
Hi-ho. Silver!
Would that be the enemy?
As a matter of fact. yes.
Good work. 2nd platoon.
We took the objective.
Who is the idiot who
cut that man's fence?
I was ordered to. sir.
By whom?
Major Horton. sir.
Major Horton?
Yes. sir.
Major Horton told you to do that?
Major Horton ordered
you to cut the fence?
Yes. he did.
Major Horton is on leave in London.
Get those cows out of here.
Lieutenant Winters.
With captain Sobel's
compliments. sir.
Lieutenant.
Oh. for crying out loud.
This spells court-martial.
No. sir. I do not understand.
Your orders to me
were to inspect the latrines
at 1000 hours.
From 0930 to 0955 I was
censoring the enlisted men's mail
by order of colonel Strayer.
At 1000 hours I followed
your orders to the minute.
I changed that time to 0945.
No one told me. sir.
I telephoned.
I'm quartered with a
family that has no telephone.
And sent a runner.
No runner found me. captain.
Irregardless. when given a
task to perform by a ranking officer
to another officer.
You failed to do so.
Were I to let such a failure of
duty by my own XO go unpunished.
What kind of message
is that to the men?
I performed my duty
as I was ordered. sir.
And I disagree.
So. your options are
quite simple. lieutenant.
Punishment for your
offenses will be denial of
a 48-hour pass
for 60 days.
Stand before
me at attention.
Or you may initiate
a letter of appeal
and request a trial
by court-martial.
You spend your weekends
on the base anyway. Dick.
Be a man.
take the punishment.
May I borrow your pen. sir?
My endorsement. sir.
I request trial
by court-martial.
We lost Winters
to battalion mess.
You're shitting me.
No.
Strayer did it. while they try
to figure out the procedures
for his court-martial.
Well. Nix better find a
loophole and get him out.
And if he don't?
Winters scrambles eggs
while the rest of us make
the big jump with Sobel.
Not me.
So we're going through
with this. right?
We've gotta do something.
Yeah.
Alright.
Good.
But we'd all better be clear
of the consequences.
I don't care about
the consequences.
We could be lined up
against a wall and shot.
Now. I'm ready to face that.
and every one of
us had better be. too.
I will not follow
that man into combat.
Me neither.
Alright.
Then let's do it.
I hereby...
no longer...
wish to serve...
as a non-commissioned officer...
in Easy company.
Alright. boys.
Good luck.
I ought to have you all shot!
This is nothing less
than an act of mutiny
while we prepare for the
goddamn invasion of Europe.
Sergeant Harris.
Yes. sir.
Turn in your stripes.
collect your gear.
You are hereby
transferred out of my regiment.
Yes. sir.
Get out.
Sergeant Ranney.
Sir.
You consider yourself lucky.
I'm only busting you to private.
All of you NCOs have
disgraced the 101st airborne.
You can consider yourself
lucky that we are on the eve
of the largest action
in the history of warfare.
which leaves me no choice.
but to spare your lives.
Now. get out of my office
and get out of my sight.
Get.
Keep 'em coming.
that-a-boy.
That's it.
I can only speculate. sir.
Most of the men would.
would never do this.
but I believe just a
few of the sergeants
may have felt their loyalty
lay more to the platoon
than to the company.
And these few sergeants convinced
all of the other NCOs in your company
to turn in their stripes?
As staff sergeants.
they have a great
amount of influence. sir.
But as I say.
the rest are good men.
I know them.
I can work with them.
This business with the
Winters' court-martial
has been an
unpleasant distraction.
Indeed.
indeed it has. sir.
However...
Your command of Easy
company has been exemplary.
Thank. thank you. sir.
In fact. except for the actions
of a few of your noncoms.
I believe you've fielded one of
the finest companies of soldiers
I've ever seen.
Yes. sir.
Herbert.
division has established
a parachute training school
at Chilton Foliat.
The idea is for
non-infantry types who...
were vital to the
coming invasion.
such as doctors and chaplains.
to take jump training there.
Frankly. I can't think of anyone
more qualified to command
such a school than you are.
Sir?
I'm reassigning you
to Chilton Foliat.
I'm losing Easy company?
The war effort
needs you elsewhere.
Permission to speak. sir?
Granted.
Is. who.
who will be replacing me?
Lieutenant Meehan
from Baker company is senior.
Good luck at
Chilton Foliat. Herbert.
Don't let us down now.
No. sir.
Carry on.
2nd platoon. listen up.
I want the 1st squad
and a-side tents right up there.
3rd squad. second row...
Holy shit.
No. it's all right.
mate. we're tommies.
not bleedin' bosch.
Is all this real?
Yeah. yeah.
Well. some of it's
from the hermans.
that somebody's
tailors knocked up.
for you lads. actually.
so. you can get your mince pies
on some of this jerry clobber.
if you know what I mean.
Not really.
Eh?
Hey. mac. you got a luger?
I'm dying to get my
hands on a real luger.
Yeah. go on then.
Quick butchers. yeah?
Boy. she sure is a doozy.
Yeah. it's pukka. innit.
What?
Hey. Petty.
Hey. mate.
You're having a bath if you
think you're half-inching that.
Oh. yeah.
Sorry.
Well. good luck.
You too. mate.
What's up. Hoobs?
These men have been
through the toughest training
the army has to offer.
Under the worst
possible circumstances.
And they volunteered for it.
Christ. Dick. I was just
shooting craps with them.
It's not like...
You know why
they volunteered?
So. when things got really
bad the man in the foxhole
next to them would be the best.
Not some draftee who's
gonna get him killed.
Are you ticked
because they like me?
Because I'm spending time
to get to know my soldiers?
I mean. c'mon. you've been
with these guys for. what.
two years?
I've been here for six days.
You're gambling. Bob.
So what. soldiers do that.
I don't deserve
a reprimand for it.
What if you'd won?
What?
What-if-you'd-won?
Never put yourself in a position
where you can take
from these men.
Lieutenant Meehan?
Enter.
On the last training jump.
I had a compass.
Close the flap.
Then we turn left.
Yeah.
Bearing zero four two.
12 minutes.
Then another left?
Yes.
Yeah.
Call it three five eight.
for 10 and a half minutes.
Green light.
right over Ramsbury.
Ramsbury.
Every single time.
Linear distance on
the grid of about...
Okay.
Ramsbury.
Upottery.
So...
It's Normandy.
st. Marie du Mont.
Causeway number one.
Causeway number two.
The ultimate field problem.
The estuary of the Douve river
divides two beachheads.
code-named Utah. here.
and Omaha. here.
Seaborne infantry will
hit these beaches in force
at a date and time
to be specified.
h-hour. d-day.
Airborne's objective.
gentlemen.
is to take the town of Careltan.
or Carentan.
thus linking Utah and Omaha
into a single continuous beachhead.
...linking Omah and Utah into
one continuous beachhead.
Each trooper will learn
this operation by heart
and know his and
every other outfits' mission
to the detail.
Lieutenant Meehan?
Yes. dukeman.
Sir. are we dropping tonight?
When it's time for you to know.
we'll let you know.
In the meantime.
study these sand tables. maps.
and reconnaissance photos
until you can draw a map
of the area by memory.
Now. we will drop
behind this Atlantic wall
five hours before the
4th infantry lands at Utah.
And between our assembly
area and the battalion's objective.
there is a German garrison
right here in this area.
st. Marie du Mont.
Easy company will
destroy that garrison.
Three day supply of k-rations.
chocolate bars. charms candy.
powdered coffee.
sugar. and matches.
Compass. bayonet.
entrenching tool.
ammunition. gas mask.
Musette bag with ammo.
my webbing. my .45. canteen.
two cartons of smokes.
Hawkins mine.
two grenades.
smoke grenade.
gamma grenade.
tnt. this bullshit.
and a pair of nasty skivvies.
What's your point?
You know. this stuff
weighs as much as I do.
I've still got my chute.
my reserve chute.
my mae west.
my m-1.
Where are you keeping
your brass knuckles?
I could use some
brass knuckles.
Sergeant Martin.
Hey. Vest.
anything for me?
No.
Sergeant Martin.
For Talbert.
Your condoms?
I don't know. probably.
What you got?
"Dear Floyd. give 'em hell."
It's from chief of the
Kokomo police department.
Right.
Whoa. you've gotta love cops.
Alright. listen up. listen up.
If you did not sign your
GI life insurance policy.
you go on over
and see sergeant Evans
at the headquarters
company tent.
You boys don't
let your families
miss out on $10.000.
You hear that. Gerry?
Hey. Lip?
Yeah. boy.
Has Guarnere said anything
to you about his brother?
No.
I got a problem.
My wife keeps up
with things back home.
casualty lists and like that.
Yeah?
Guarnere's brother in Italy?
Henry?
Killed in Monte Cassino.
Well. I'm sure he doesn't know.
Damn.
What'd you think I should do?
If it were me. I'd tell him.
Couple of hours before we jump?
I don't know.
Why they springing
these things on us now?
It's just an extra 80 pounds
strapped to your leg.
Does anybody have any idea
how the hell this thing works?
Colonel Sink.
"Soldiers of the regiment:
tonight is the night
of nights.
Today. as you read this.
you are en route
to the great adventure for
which you have trained for
over two years."
So. that's why they
gave us ice cream.
Easy company. listen up!
Channel coast is socked
in with rain and fog.
No jump tonight.
The invasion has
been postponed.
We're on a 24-hour
stand-down.
Well. this is quite a surprise.
Not particularly.
It so happens I rather expected it.
Well. I can't see how you
people can pass up $80.000
for the cause.
For whose cause?
If you're so interested
in serving a cause.
why don't you join the army?
Next. please.
Oh. 4-m.
You look 1-A to me.
Hey. you don't look
so bad yourself.
"Dearest Johnny."
Well. should you
be giving blood?
I woke up.
I got the wrong
goddamn jacket.
Shh.
I was struck by lightning.
Nobody dancing.
It doesn't matter.
"Your pal.
Bill Guarnere's brother..."
Good luck. lads.
See you. Tommy.
See you. mate.
Try and get these
leg straps through.
Johnny?
Got something you
might be looking for.
Took your jacket by mistake.
I'm sorry.
You read it?
Where the fuck
is Monte Cassino?
I don't know.
Italy somewhere.
Sorry about your brother. Bill
He was. er...
Let's get this over with.
Bill?
I'll meet up with you over there.
Gentlemen. doc Roe is handing
these out for air sickness.
Orders are.
every man takes one now.
another 30 minutes in the air.
Lieutenant.
2nd platoon. listen up.
Good luck.
God bless you.
I'll see you in the
assembly area.
If the wire constant is sensitive.
then I think all we should
have to deal with is...
Goddamn. Lieb.
That airsick pill is
making me loopy.
Subs cleaned up by
Operations and Kungen
Do you want subtitles for any video?
-=[ ai.OpenSubtitles.com ]=-